Nathalia Serrano

Email me: nathaliaserranoa@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathalia-serrano-924631114/

Call me: +1 647 299 1468

Address: 121 Acorn Place, Mississauga, ON.

Software Developer

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Lawyer and software developer transitioning from the legal sector to the technology industry, with 4 years of experience in negotiation, risk management, project structuring, decision-making and problem-solving, and 2 years of practical experience in programming. I have successfully collaborated with interdisciplinary teams to achieve common goals in a corporate environment, and I am looking forward to applying my skills in the tech industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, Java, C#. Frameworks: .NET, Angular, Node.js, React Native.

Front-end Development: HTML, CSS. API and Database: MongoDB, SQL.

Microsoft Office Suite: Excel, Word, Outlook, Power Other tools: Visio, Draw.io, Monday.com.

Point.

PORTFOLIO: https://nathaliaserranoanaya.github.io/Portfolio/

LANGUAGES: Native Spanish and English speaker.

EDUCATION

UDEMY | THE COMPLETE 2024 SOFTWARE TESTING BOOTCAMP | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | February 2024

UDEMY | 100 DAYS OF CODE: THE COMPLETE PYTHON PRO BOOTCAMP | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | February 2024

CENTENNIAL COLLEGE | SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN | Toronto, ON | August 2022 – December 2023 Relevant Courses: Web Interface Design, Client-Side Web Development, Java Programming, Web Application Development, Software Systems Design, Software Testing and Quality Assurance, Introduction to Database Concepts and Advanced Database Concepts.

GPA: 3.8 / 4.5

PLATZI | JAVASCRIPT PRACTICAL COURSE | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | July 2022

PLATZI | JAVASCRIPT COURSE | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | June 2022

PLATZI | PROGRAMMING COURSE | ONLINE CERTIFIED COURSE | June 2022

LOS ANDES UNIVERSITY | BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN LAW | Bogota, Colombia | January 2013 – December 2017 Relevant Courses: Commercial and Business Law, Consumer Law, Arbitration, Mergers and Acquisitions.

GPA: 4.2 / 5.0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CINE COLOMBIA - LAWYER; Bogotá (Colombia) November 2018 - July 2022

Cine Colombia is the most important entertainment company in Colombia and one of the best in customer service and technology in Latin America, focused on the distribution and exhibition of films.

- Negotiated and drafted contracts and legal documents in collaboration with other departments of the company, ensuring compliance with relevant regulations and successful project execution.
- Researched and analyzed regulations related to intellectual property, commercial law, consumer law, and personal data to effectively address legal challenges, provide legal advice, and ensure the company's compliance.
- Coordinated the execution of IT, construction, and marketing projects to ensure seamless integration of legal considerations into their execution.
- Supported the customer service department by providing strategic responses to complex client complaints to mitigate the risk of liability and created legal strategies, which contributed to the successful resolution of complex customer service cases.
- Documented project specifications and stages to reflect the understanding among all project stakeholders in the contracts, ensuring clear expectations and successful execution.
- Maintained positive relationships with external law firms, actively participating in project-related discussions, and ensuring alignment with the company's objectives.
- Significantly reduced the risk of liability and fines through collaboration with the marketing team in structuring advertising campaigns to ensure legal compliance with consumer regulations across all our products and services.

SANABRIA GOMEZ LAW FIRM - JUNIOR LAWYER; Bogotá (Colombia) March 2018 - November 2018

- Drafted and reviewed insurance contracts and other legal documents to ensure clarity, accuracy, and legal compliance, and protect the interests of the clients, minimize ambiguities, and establish clear terms and obligations for all parties involved.
- Performed the review of policies and contracts to prepare legal defense in litigation related to the civil liability.
- Conducted research and analysis on insurance laws, regulations, and relevant case law to ensure a thorough understanding and compliance within the claims handling process.
- Planned and executed legal defense strategies for civil liability cases, demonstrating a strategic approach within the legal context.
- Maintained records for all correspondence and documents related to contracts, contributing to efficient project tracking and documentation.

LOS ANDES UNIVERSITY - TEACHER'S ASSISTANT; Bogotá (Colombia), July 2015 - June 2016

- Enhanced lesson preparation efficiency by collaborating with the lead teacher in organizing materials and setting up equipment.
- Promoted student engagement and achievement by facilitating personalized and small group assistance to support individual student objectives.